Hello English learners and welcome to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎来到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
I'm Amira.
我是Amira。
Amira and I are here today with an interesting lesson about a hotel situation.
今天Amira和我带来了一堂有趣的课程，关于酒店里的一个情景。
Amira, why don't you give us a little bit more information?
Amira，你给我们多介绍一点情况吧？
Well, the situation is taking place in a hotel and someone is checking in and is obtaining
好的，这个情景发生在酒店里，有人正在办理入住，并且得到了
an upgrade.
升级。
An upgrade, okay, that's an interesting word.
升级，好吧，这个词挺有意思的。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue and then we'll come back and explain all this vocabulary.
我们先听一下对话，然后回来解释这些词汇。
Good afternoon.
下午好。
What can I do for you?
有什么能为您效劳的吗？
I'd like to check in please.
我想办理入住。
I have a reservation under the name Anthony Roberts.
我用Anthony Roberts的名字预订了房间。
All right.
好的。
Roberts.
Roberts。
Oh, Mr. Roberts, we've been expecting you.
哦，Roberts先生，我们一直在等您。
And here is your key card to the presidential suite.
这是您的总统套房房卡。
But there must be some mistake.
但一定是搞错了。
My reservation was for a standard room.
我预订的是标准间。
Are you sure?
您确定吗？
Let me double check.
让我再核对一下。
Yeah, here, this is my confirmation number.
是的，这里，这是我的确认号码。
You're right, Mr. Roberts.
您说得对，Roberts先生。
There seems to be a mix up.
好像出了点混乱。
Unfortunately, we're overbooked at the moment.
不幸的是，我们现在超额预订了。
So?
那怎么办？
Not to worry.
别担心。
We're pleased to offer you a complimentary upgrade.
我们很高兴为您提供免费升级。
Presidential suite, baby!
总统套房，太棒了！
Okay, everyone, that is nice, huh?
好了，各位，这不错吧？
Yeah, the guy is really excited that he's gonna get the presidential suite.
是啊，这家伙因为能住总统套房而非常兴奋。
Yes, there's some interesting phrases and vocabulary items here.
是的，这里有一些有趣的短语和词汇。
And I know, Marco, you want to talk about some of them.
我知道，Marco，你想谈谈其中一些。
Right, the first one, and this is really useful for all of our listeners who travel a lot.
对，第一个，这对我们经常旅行的听众来说非常有用。
This phrase will come in handy and it is, I have a reservation under the name.
这个短语会派上用场，就是：I have a reservation under the name.
Under the name.
以……的名字。
So before we explain this phrase, let's listen to some examples on how it is used in other
在我们解释这个短语之前，先听一些它在其他情境中使用的例子，
situations and then we'll come back and give you more information.
然后我们再回来给你更多信息。
Alright some really good examples there on how we could use this phrase in other situations.
好的，这里有一些很好的例子，展示了我们如何在其他情况下使用这个短语。
But just in case, let me explain it real fast.
但以防万一，让我快速解释一下。
Under the name means that when you go to the restaurant or a hotel and you tell them your
以……的名义预订意味着当你去餐厅或酒店时，你告诉他们你的
name, they know that you are the person that they have been expecting, they have been waiting.
名字，他们就知道你就是他们一直在等待的那个人。
Yes.
是的。
Well, I have chosen another useful phrase for you and it is mix up.
嗯，我为你选了另一个有用的短语，那就是 mix up。
Mix up.
Mix up。
There seems to be a mix up.
好像搞混了。
Before we talk about this phrase, let's listen to some examples of how it is used.
在我们讨论这个短语之前，先听一些使用它的例子。
There was a mix up at the airport and my bags were sent to Antarctica.
机场出了点混乱，我的行李被送到了南极洲。
I'm sorry sir, there's been a terrible mix up.
对不起，先生，出了个大乌龙。
We've given you the wrong baby.
我们抱错了孩子。
Okay that was useful and funny.
好吧，这既有用又有趣。
Yeah, that's the baby situation.
是啊，就是那个抱错孩子的情况。
Oh my god.
哦，我的天哪。
I can't imagine that happening.
我无法想象那种事会发生。
Yeah, I know.
是啊，我知道。
Well guys, so a mix up is a confusion or a misunderstanding.
好了，各位，mix up 指的是混乱或误解。
Exactly, well put.
没错，说得好。
Alright Marco, what do you have for us?
好的，Marco，你给我们准备了什么？
Okay, the next word that we should take a look at is overbooked.
好的，下一个我们要看的词是 overbooked。
Overbooked.
Overbooked。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
So if a hotel or a flight is overbooked, it means that they are full.
如果酒店或航班 overbooked，意思是它们已经满了。
They are more than full.
它们超员了。
Right, so they cannot accept any more people.
对，所以他们不能再接待更多人了。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, now why is this phrase useful?
好的，为什么这个短语有用？
Because it happens all the time.
因为它经常发生。
There's so many other situations where you can use this word or hear it from other native
还有很多其他情况你可以使用这个词，或者从其他母语
English speakers.
为英语的人那里听到它。
For example, a bus or a train can be overbooked.
例如，公交车或火车也可能 overbooked。
Exactly, that's really common.
没错，这很常见。
Okay, let's take a look at the last phrase for today and that is complimentary upgrade.
好的，我们来看今天最后一个短语：complimentary upgrade。
Complimentary upgrade.
Complimentary upgrade。
免费升级。
So this means that, for example, when the hotel is overbooked and all of their standard
所以这意味着，例如，当酒店超额预订，所有标准
rooms are full, they will give you a better room, a more expensive room, but free.
房间都满了，他们会给你一个更好的房间，更贵的房间，但是免费的。
Yes, because it was not your fault.
是的，因为这不是你的错。
Right, this also happens sometimes, if you're lucky, on airplane flights.
对，这种情况有时也会发生在飞机上，如果你运气好的话。
Yes.
是的。
So if you are in economy class and an airplane, but for some reason it's overbooked, they
所以如果你在飞机经济舱，但由于某种原因超售了，他们
will move you to business class or first class for free.
会免费把你升到商务舱或头等舱。
I have a similar story, but I'm not going to tell you about it now.
我也有类似的故事，但现在不打算告诉你。
For now, let's go and listen to the dialogue one more time and when we come back, we'll
现在，让我们再听一遍对话，等我们回来时，我们会
talk some more.
再聊一些。
Good afternoon, what can I do for you?
下午好，有什么能帮您的吗？
I'd like to check in, please.
我想办理入住。
I have a reservation under the name Anthony Roberts.
我用安东尼·罗伯茨的名字预订了房间。
All right, Roberts.
好的，罗伯茨。
Oh, Mr. Roberts, we've been expecting you and here is your key card to the presidential
哦，罗伯茨先生，我们一直在等您，这是您总统套房的房卡。
suite.
套房。
But there must be some mistake.
但一定是搞错了。
My reservation was for a standard room.
我预订的是标准间。
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
Let me double check.
让我再核对一下。
Yeah, here, this is my confirmation number.
是的，这里，这是我的确认号码。
You're right, Mr. Roberts, there seems to be a mix up.
您说得对，罗伯茨先生，好像搞混了。
Unfortunately, we're overbooked at the moment.
不幸的是，我们现在超额预订了。
So?
所以呢？
Not to worry, we're pleased to offer you a complimentary upgrade.
别担心，我们很高兴为您提供免费升级。
Woohoo!
哇哦！
Presidential suite, baby!
总统套房，宝贝！
I love listening to this dialogue.
我喜欢听这段对话。
It's just so nice to see that someone is enjoying his upgrade so much.
看到有人如此享受他的升级，真是太好了。
Yeah, especially since he was expecting just a really normal room and now he's going to
是啊，尤其是他本来只期待一个普通的房间，现在却要
be treated like a king.
被当作国王一样对待。
So Marco, have you ever gotten a complimentary upgrade?
那么马可，你曾经得到过免费升级吗？
Yes, yes, I did.
是的，是的，我得到过。
When I was traveling through India, I bought a normal seat in the train.
当我在印度旅行时，我买了一张火车普通座位票。
But for some reason, it was overbooked.
但不知什么原因，火车超售了。
So I talked to the station manager and I got a complimentary upgrade to first class.
所以我和车站经理谈了谈，然后免费升级到了头等舱。
I had a similar experience as well.
我也有类似的经历。
I was flying from Shanghai to Qatar and I actually had an economy seat, but for some
我从上海飞往多哈，实际上我坐的是经济舱，但不知
reason they just upgraded me and I was so happy.
什么原因他们给我升了舱，我太高兴了。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
Like it wasn't overbooked?
就像没有超售一样？
Well, I'm not sure because normally the night flight is not that full, but they upgraded
嗯，我不太确定，因为通常夜间航班没那么满，但他们给我升舱了
me for some reason and I was so happy.
不知为什么，我当时特别开心。
It was an upgrade to first class.
是升到头等舱。
Wow, that's really cool.
哇，那真是太棒了。
I would prefer a first class upgrade on an airplane, yeah, any day.
我宁愿在飞机上被升到头等舱，嗯，任何时候都行。
Well, you know what really amazed me was like the food you get there.
嗯，你知道最让我惊讶的是什么吗？是那里的食物。
You know, you have a five course meal.
你知道吗，有五道菜的大餐。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
Yes.
是的。
And you get all the drinks you can get, right?
而且你能喝到所有你能喝的饮料，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Yeah, I would be really happy there.
是啊，我在那里会非常开心。
All right, everyone, we're out of time today, but be sure to listen tomorrow because we'll
好了，各位，今天的时间到了，但一定要明天收听，因为我们会
be back again with another great podcast.
带着另一期精彩的播客回来。
And also, don't forget to go to our website at EnglishPod.com and leave us all your questions
另外，别忘了访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，在社区论坛上给我们留下所有问题
and comments in our community forum.
和评论。
Yes, and we would also appreciate your suggestions.
是的，我们也非常感谢你的建议。
And I hope you enjoyed the lesson today and Marco and I will be back tomorrow with another
希望你喜欢今天的课程，马可和我明天会带着另一期节目回来。
great lesson for you.
这节课很棒。
But for now, it's bye!
但现在，再见啦！